<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Why SQL Components on My Docs</title><link>/docs/why/</link><description>Recent content in Why SQL Components on My Docs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright (c) 2020-2024 Thulite</copyright><atom:link href="/docs/why/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SQL Builders</title><link>/docs/why/sql-builders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/why/sql-builders/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SQL Builders&lt;/strong> are tools designed to simplify database interaction by abstracting away complex SQL queries and connection management. They help developers focus on writing business logic rather than managing database connections and handling raw SQL queries. Popular SQL Builders like &lt;strong>Spring JDBC&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>QueryDSL&lt;/strong> allow developers to construct SQL queries programmatically, making code more readable and maintainable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>JPA</title><link>/docs/why/jpa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/why/jpa/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Java Persistence API (JPA)&lt;/strong> is a well-known framework that abstracts most of the database interaction for Java applications by utilizing &lt;strong>Object-Relational Mapping (ORM)&lt;/strong>. JPA handles both &lt;strong>connection management&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>DAO implementation&lt;/strong>, leaving the developer to focus on defining &lt;strong>model classes&lt;/strong> and mapping them to database tables.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jooq</title><link>/docs/why/jooq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/why/jooq/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>JOOQ&lt;/strong> (Java Object Oriented Querying) is a powerful and widely-used Java framework for building type-safe SQL queries. JOOQ’s primary goal is to seamlessly integrate SQL into Java code by generating Java classes from a database schema, enabling developers to work with SQL in a type-safe, programmatic way.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>