<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>API Guide on My Docs</title><link>/docs/guides/</link><description>Recent content in API Guide on My Docs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright (c) 2020-2024 Thulite</copyright><atom:link href="/docs/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics</title><link>/docs/guides/basics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/guides/basics/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>SQL Components&lt;/strong> simplifies how your Java application interacts with relational databases by providing three core concepts:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>DataManager&lt;/strong>: Handles database connections and manages access to various database objects.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Model&lt;/strong>: Represents the structure of database tables as simple Java objects (POJOs).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Store&lt;/strong>: An interface that allows you to perform common database operations like &lt;strong>Select&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Insert&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Update&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>Delete&lt;/strong> on tables.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Table</title><link>/docs/guides/table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/guides/table/</guid><description>&lt;p>Store will act as inteface for all the SQL operations againts tables. For.eg For Movie table, you can get the Store from DataManages as given below&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Stored Procedure</title><link>/docs/guides/stored-procedure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/guides/stored-procedure/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Stored Procedures&lt;/strong> are a powerful feature in relational databases that allow you to encapsulate SQL logic on the database side. A stored procedure is a precompiled set of one or more SQL statements that can perform complex operations like updates, inserts, and even condition handling. By moving logic into stored procedures, you can reduce the amount of database interaction from your application code, increase performance, and improve maintainability.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>